hello and good morning and welcome to
this
lesson all about creating exceptional
quality content as well as getting into
the mindset to serve your clients well
this is a topic
that um quite
frankly I have been insecure about for a
long time and I have also been harshly
judged for for a long time and I've come
out of that because here's the thing I
don't like to teach things if I'm still
insecure about
it I don't like to teach things in this
setting if
I'm struggling with self-doubt and worry
about it now there's there comes a time
where it's okay to press through that I
don't make that a
rule
um but I have developed a methodology to
break out of self-doubt and
insecurity that whether I'm feeling it
or not sometimes I could literally feel
self-doubt and
insecurity in the morning when I wake up
and then I have a process that I go
through to break me out of it and then I
could see a comment on social media from
a rude person that snaps me right back
into
it
later and now I'm like okay I got to go
to work and figure out what that was
happened yesterday literally um I was
supposed to record this training right
here last
night and just couldn't and in fact I
had to just I just had to go to sleep
and it it took me I've been up since uh
3:00 in the morning it's taken me about
3 hours just to process
through uh the last night and all that
to feel the confidence to be able to
teach this to you because it's such a
deep area for me and in fact the comment
that the person made on my social media
was a
direct mental
attack I don't like using the word
attack but like my brain attached to it
and it literally was the very thing
that would shut
down um my ability to teach this lesson
today isn't that
interesting it's very interesting and so
then by processing through that I've
come out the other
side um and listen I you know what's
amazing is I've learned how to not let
that affect my family life I didn't know
how to do that a couple months ago I
learned how to not let it affect my
client
life couldn't do that about about a year
ago um and I've learned how to not let
it take over my life
recently you know we had a a thing in
the accelerator group where I wasn't
answering questions and sales copy and
things like that sometimes for up to six
six days um
um
and you
know
uh that can happen
sometimes where you see a distraction
something takes your focus off and
that's really the biggest thing is it's
distractions and it's learning to
control your distractions number one
there's a great book that I do recommend
called
indistractable how to control your
attention and choose your life um and it
was written by a guy who studied about
how social media distracts us and and
the different apps that we have and
things like this and and all of that and
what distracts us and pulls us off track
to help us with our focus and our
relationships and just you know I've
read this book twice I haven't read it
in in a long time but the lessons keep
coming back to me and so I recommend it
in an age of ever increasing demands for
our attention how do we get the best
from technology without letting it get
the best of us it's it's a it's a
powerful book um highly highly recommend
it there's free bonuses you can go
grab um the author is amazing that I
love the even just you know the people
who are endorsing the book I mean it's
it's endorsed by some of the some of the
best uh minds of our of Our Generation
and so and he wrote another book some of
y'all might enjoy called hooked how to
build habit forming products he you know
it basically is the Playbook of Silicon
Valley creating the most uh addictive
products and
processes on the
planet and I've actually not read hooked
but I've heard a lot of great things
about it it's in multiple languages
because what it is is it's it's it's
literally
about what it takes to create products
in techn techology that keep people
using them and keep them engaged okay so
if you want to know how to keep people
engaged hooked is where it's at uh and
then what he said was he almost felt
like a moral obligation to write this
one it's how to get
unhooked it's like the it's like the
methadone uh to and he was joking on
that you know like this is uh like you
get addicted to the to the uh to the
opiate to the crack and then this is
what gets you unhooked as far as that
goes and the thing is is most all of us
are using addictive products that use
exactly what he's teaching in this book
right here um this is about how to like
not let things distract us and it breaks
down the psychology and the science
behind distraction it's incredible um
just to learn and understand that
okay what I I'm not talking about that
though here today what I want to talk
about is um once you can learn to
control those
distractions which again that's been a
it's been a journey for me for a long
time uh that I have struggled struggled
with that I have dealt with that I have
tried to do
um once you learn to control those
distractions now we got to figure out
okay how do I um very
quickly wire my brain
situationally to do the things that I
need to need to do and this came by
necessity for
me as a father with my one-year-old and
so what I'm about to do is pass on to
you some lessons that I have
learned being a father for 15
months um so that you don't need whether
you have children or not um you're going
to be able to learn some really cool
stuff that I've learned that has allowed
me to reduce my work hours to where I
actually get to spend more time with my
son and my wife and and like I'm living
the happiest life I've ever lived right
now on a daily
basis um this is also the result of
about 3 years of
therapy and all of that um with you okay
so again but I'm not a therapist I'm not
a psychiatrist I am not certified in any
of the stuff that I'm teaching here
today do not treat any of this as a way
of practicing medicine or anything like
that one thing that I would recommend
though is below this lesson you're going
to see the transcript okay and we teach
you how to use chat
GPT a prompt that you could literally
use is is copy and paste that whole
transcript and before you copy and paste
it type into chat
GPT something like this I have a
transcript from a lesson all
about the content of the lesson below
you you don't even need to actually tell
it what the content is you can literally
just tell it all about the content below
and be like oh okay and then the AI will
literally be like what's the content
about and it'll figure it out um it's a
little hack to save you a lot of time
and effort to not know what the right
prompt is you literally just tell it
it's all about the content below
no like if you told a normal person that
it would be like what but telling AI
that it actually is a little
hack to save you a lot of headaches um I
have questions about this content and by
the way you can use this for any of the
transcripts that we have in the members
area here
to save you a lot of time and to ask
questions of chat gbt for certain things
okay um please read and
review the transcript and then let's
proceed to answer my questions okay so
like for instance I could literally just
take uh this lesson right here about
mastering group dynamics copy and paste
it I press contrl C or contrl a so
that's that's how I did it so quickly
contr a it grabs the whole page I don't
care if it grabs complete continue all
that extra
stuff press contrl C to copy it contrl V
right there paste it chat jpt grab the
whole
thing and then I can ask questions on
the
Fly great I reviewed the transcript it
covers comprehensive approach to
managing and optimizing group coaching
Dynamics focusing on engagement value
delivery adapting setting boundaries can
I assist you with other question so like
that's a great way by the way to um even
with your own content to unpack new
things like for instance here's the one
thing that I like to do can you
brainstorm 20 ideas for YouTube videos
based on the topic above that might go
viral and
attract people to buy this training from
the
above transcript okay okay so I'm
showing you this and also teaching you
something at the same time you could
literally do this with any piece of
content with any transcript and anything
like this on YouTube every piece of
video that exists on YouTube has a
transcript that is
publicly
available
okay so like this is a this is a NASCAR
podcast that I just love from Dale
Earhart Jr I've been I've been obsessed
with NASCAR my whole life and I've
gotten recently gotten back into
it and so anyways um because those guys
are really wealthy they got a lot of
money they got way and they're and they
don't flaunt it that much and I like
that anyways you can pause any video on
YouTube basically go to the description
click on show
transcript and then I click on these
three dots and I click toggle timestamps
I turn those off and then you see how
this Scrolls you I scroll to the top you
click here and then you hold your mouse
down so you got to do this on a
computer and then scroll all the way to
the bottom right
here and you can literally do this with
chat GPT as
well uh almost like the same
prompt
that we did right here this is all going
to make sense like in like five minutes
while I'm showing you all
this I'm sure you have no interest in
masar but this is all going to make
sense in like five minutes okay so again
same same prompting we should probably
add that to our prompt
document
um yeah let's add
this me scroll down
to should do um answer
questions about a
transcript I'm going add that one right
there okay cool and I want to and I want
to start updating the prompt document to
start to add some of these because a lot
of people are like they rely on this a
lot and so you
know hopefully this is helpful to some
people all right so let me just take
like this Dale junr one right here
I could even go through and I could copy
the title
description and a bunch of the comments
even some of the top comments whatever
those are literally just like
copy so like I'm crowdsourcing so much
information just by doing
this opinions and
everything it's kind of incredible and I
could sort
by yep top comments
exactly boom top
comments this is a great way just any
video you find on YouTube you can
literally unpack it dive
deeper start asking questions so I don't
even know what this video is sounds like
you shared about various topics related
to financial decisions personal interest
what does it say about Dale's uh
Financial uh mindset here we go so again
I don't even know what the video is
about transcript review is quite a bit
of about his mindset showcasing someone
who's both cautious and thoughtful about
his spending it's
amazing and you could do this with
literally any transcript as far as this
goes and then unpack any topic Deeper by
doing this okay so this is one aspect of
brainstorming for content for you you
can either Brainstorm by using other
people's
transcripts this way to come up with
like new ideas as far as this
goes um and so
so then what I could do is I could
literally
take this that it unpacked right here
can you can you um brainstorm 20
possible ideas for Content that a
financial literacy coach could teach
that borrows from the lessons above and
the
following so now like if you're a
financial literacy coach literally just
taking that video if I liked it if I'm
feeling something from it now this gives
me brainstormed ideas if you find a
viral video of some kind from some
YouTuber that you like that's why
YouTube is really starting to be a great
resource for us this can then help you
brainstorm that lessons from the rich
and famous overcoming Financial anxiety
I mean literally this is like a master
class right here on on content and even
courses that you could create just from
a podcast episode from a NASCAR
driver imagine how much better it would
be if you pulled it from somebody that's
in your own industry see what I'm
saying okay so again group coaching
Dynamics same type of a thing secret to
engaging your group audience why people
thrive in group coaching others don't
mastering group dynamics how to
create high value coaching environment
top mistakes coaches make leveraging
technology the future of coaching and
AI
okay build a community around a program
and so like I'm even showing you
how I you're able you can literally get
the most out of the accelerator by using
AI this way and using it with YouTube
because this is how I brainstorm stuff
all the time myself
okay so there's that idea right now
right there okay now here's something
that I want to set I want I just want to
try
out are there are there any forms of
entertainment
media that deal with the
same uh Lane Vibe or
topic of the
above content and
brainstormed ideas such as music
songs
movies fictional
books or
even other that haven't been
mentioned that I can look at okay and
please don't check out here when I'm
talking about this some of y'all check
out when I talk about anything related
to
entertainment I need you to not do this
I need you to not check
out when I'm talking about
entertainment
okay
because you may not understand why this
is important and I and I and I get
that but this is one of the most
effective ways for you to actually
become the best
coach and one of the best teachers you
can possibly
be so we're going to use these two
examples group dynamics and the NASCAR
one with the same
exact question
the King speech Coach Carter by the way
these are great movies Dead Poet
Society the
intern Tuesdays with
Mory lean in read that
book Seven Habits of Highly affected
people so again these are even all
daring greatly I love that book so so
again uh let's see I of the Tiger
Survivor okay beautiful day by you
too Tim Ferris
show how I built this those these are
all great podcasts that I love on
being TED
Talks these media selections
entertainment inspiration insights into
the Dynamics of mentorship can you give
me even more examples of
entertainment in the
categories
above certainly here's additional
examples and I love doing this Freedom
Writers again I love that movie as well
these are liter oh my gosh fighting
Forest these are literally movies that
influenced me as a
kid queer ey queery is actually a great
show on how to do like a group group
dynamic that's amazing my set the new
psychology of
success uh the art of possibility The
Alchemist dare to lead I've not read The
Alchemist art of possibility let's see
Hall of Fame by The Script and Will I Am
Unwritten by Natasha
bingfield okay Tony Robbins
podcast now here's this what I I was
trying to get it to give me more music
can you give me 20 more songs related to
All the
Above the vibe the tone the story The
the goals the outcome of the content of
group dynamics Etc okay watch
this some of y'all I don't know how much
music y'all listen to but Apple
music is
streaming um and Spotify and you can
build playlists and you can
literally build a playlist
these are by the way these are all
incredible songs right here if I built
this playlist right here even me just
reading these songs I'm
remembering what the songs are okay pop
Anthem Lose Yourself by Eminem on top of
the world Unstoppable by
CA Titanium by David
Gua Shake It Off by Taylor
Swift
yep yeah so anyway
this gets you into that kind of like it
repeated the same song that's funny into
like the vibe
of what we're trying to accomplish even
in lessons like this now for copyright
purposes I can't actually play these
songs on the video here but I could
literally build a playlist of the ones
it just
mentioned and listen to
that to get me ready for this lesson
right here I could turn on some of these
movies in the background I could
literally turn on Coach Carter right now
on my TV to prepare while I'm washing
dishes or things like this so that's why
I subscribe to all these different
streaming video platforms and things
like
that because a sh a movie like Coach
Carter by I'll tell you this that I love
that Coach Carter if y'all have never
seen Coach Carter it's
legitimately a master class in coaching
and what a good coach
does is he perfect no made mistakes but
it's
inspiring and if You' never seen Coach
Carter I highly recommend it if you've
never seen Freedom Writers too I
recommend
it this is another
one cuz she led and
coached and and by the way she's amazing
I mean my my
son oh wait that's Hillary Swank that's
not um gosh she looks so much like the
other the other gal she looks a lot like
um the gal
that you
swing it's a they type cast in Hollywood
who's the one uh Jennifer
Garner yeah they're they have a similar
like look to them for
sure um and that's like you know that's
type casting is how is how Hollywood
casts certain characters you
know um yeah Freedom Writers
incredible Coach Carter
incredible about group dynamics y'all
could literally learn
lessons
that go deeper into what I
taught about this
course just by
simply watching some of these movies
that are mentioned
here
finding Forester story of unique
mentorship between a reclusive writer
and a pro a prodigious young
African-American scholar
athlete um Dead Poet Society that's
another good
one with Robin
Williams again because he's this he's a
mentor to these
boys is it perfect no none of these are
perfect these are movies
they're
emotional they're not meant for you to
model your life
after they're
entertainment but they teach
lessons and they'll get you if you watch
entertainment they get you into the vibe
and the feeling that you're looking for
so that's exactly what I did this
morning as I turned on a certain
playlist of music movies I did so last
night and I don't even watch the whole
movie either sometimes I might go back
and finish it that's another thing too
like when it comes to entertainment you
don't need to listen to the whole song
once you're getting what you want out of
it if you're using it for this purpose
you don't need to finish it you can
literally just use it for the thing that
you're wanting to use it
for okay see same thing right right here
Mo Money Mo Problems by notorious bi.
rich girl Wolf of Wall Street Pursuit of
Happiness yeah that's great richest man
in Babylon Rich Dad Poor Dad Shark Tank
billions these are all great pieces of
content kind of gets you in the mindset
of what Dale Jr is talking about right
here yeah so
cool and so like let's let's let's
create like um can you brainstorm 20
more
songs you know
let's see let's see if it can come up
with more like more songs like a songs
list Money by Pink Floyd price tag Can't
Buy Me
Love thrift shop and listen some of
these songs I you know I wouldn't I
wouldn't be feeling if you're not
feeling a song Skip it don't use
it Thrift Shop's a good one
though if I had a million dollars
uh the
opportunity Mo Money Mo Problems rich
girl gold digger
yep billionaire by Travy
McCoy and so the idea is you can
literally use chat
jpt and entertainment
media to help tap you into certain
certain mindsets and things like this
are there
any video games or video
game game series
that involve the topics above or might
include similar skill sets or mental
Frameworks even that indirectly might
encourage the above uh Vibe or goals
okay I ask this all the time too of it
and then I'll literally go grab like if
I'm really wanting to learn something if
I'm wanting to teach something by the
way this comes from learning and
teaching some of y'all might have been
watching this for 27 minutes and your
brain is checking out and you're just
like I don't understand I literally just
bought the Animal Crossing series
like the other day I just bought a copy
of Animal
Crossing for this exact purpose and I
didn't even realize it I just
intuitively was like I think Animal
Crossing is going to help me Teach
certain Concepts to
people this is amazing stardew Valley
exactly Farming Simulator Roller Coaster
Tycoon City skyline Wall Street
Raider capitalism
2 so these are video games even that
could get you into a certain Vibe
Monopoly Monopoly is a great
one let's try this for like the group
coaching Dynamics this will be
interesting what we see right here it's
probably going to be like Heroes Journey
type based stuff like RPGs and things
like that and maybe sports
games we'll
see life is strange Series yeah that's a
good good
one Legend of
Zelda
exactly Persona yeah person that's right
Persona
yeah Final Fantasy these are literally
game series that I've played over the
years undertale never played that one I
would say like games like FIFA or even
like NHL and stuff too um what about
games like FIFA or
NHL or
Madden
or NBA teamb based sports games I'm
curious to see what it says about that
can you unpack this
multi-dimensionally Skyrim yeah these
are literally all game series that I
have poured myself over and over and
over and over and over again which is
crazy and it's l and it's helped me to
become better at the coaching and all
that let's see Team base Rich
multi-dimensional experience and not
simulate physical aspects technical
skills improving and technical skills
strategic thinking
yeah so again what this is doing is it's
a it's all about getting your
brain wired into a
mindset that is able to
accomplish the things things that you're
trying to
do even if they are difficult or hard or
you get distracted or things come up or
stuff like
that you're able
to tap right
in be
engaged and not disconnected even when
you got chaos going on in your life you
can actually
use certain forms of media and
entertainment
which actually seems to serve better
than non-fiction
sometimes to get you engaged into the
thinking and stuff like that may even
just reading this type of stuff right
here because I have engaged with all of
these different forms of media it's
literally triggered neurotransmitters in
my brain to tap me right into what I'm
teaching right now into the vibe that
I'm wanting to do and what I'm trying to
present and stuff like that and so for
me as a teacher for me to show up
in this group to be able to give advice
and Clarity on content and create
content and this has also helped me to
improve how I express myself I do this
when I'm Consulting a client I do this
when I'm doing a one-on-one coaching I
do this when I'm about to go into a hard
experience or something that I've not
done before or things like that because
it helps break me out of
the emotional and mental anxiety and
things like that to be able to engage on
these different levels
okay so that's what I wanted to just
share with you is that for you to be
able to go to the next level of where
you want to go when it comes to creating
content when it comes to teaching your
audience is learn
to wire your
neurotransmitters in a
way that is
conducive
to you being the best possible version
of yourself as a coach or
mentor and so what we consume what comes
into us if you're just watching content
that makes you angry or upset or numbs
you out or things like that take a break
from that maybe for an afternoon or or a
day I mean for me that's exactly what I
do I'll take a break from stuff and I'll
spend all night and in the morning
just Med and when I talk about
meditating it's not even like sitting
down and just meditating anymore it's
like I'm doing other things I'm playing
these video games I'm watching these
movies I'm engaging I'm going on my
treadmill and reading books I might
download it on Kindle that's why Kindle
unlimited is also really really cool for
that you get access to all these
different books and so and chat GPT is
like having access to a ton of books as
well cuz chat jpt can literally break
down for you certain Concepts as far as
this goes okay so anyways I hope that
this was helpful for you some of yall
might be watching this and you're still
kind of not connecting the dots is to
what I'm sharing would love for you to
ask questions in the group on some of
our group calls about some of this and
how to use this for yourself maybe I can
bring some
clarity and that's one of the number one
things when it comes to group dynamics
is I'm able to answer your questions if
you're expecting me to have the perfect
exact answer that you're needing in my
trainings and lessons that's an
unreasonable expectation and and if
you're holding yourself to that same
standard no wonder you've not created
your own courses no wonder you've not
put your own content out there and so
realize this is a group coaching program
and membership to where you go through a
training like this and then you ask one
question in the group and then I'm a
able to answer or have a dialogue back
and forth maybe you don't like that kind
of interaction you just want the course
to give you all the right
content uh
it's not how this works so that's not
the best way to actually engage things
if you're wanting to actually create a
program that actually truly highly
engages people and produces results for
people you got to also learn how to
break past some of the stuff that maybe
makes you feel
uncomfortable chat GPT can be very
helpful to help you figure out you know
maybe why you feel uncomfortable with
this let's ask this why would someone
feel
uncomfortable asking questions in a
group about the subject matter and
getting angry that the group leader
didn't teach something in the main
lesson because this helps me even
understand maybe where people are coming
from as far as that goes and I'm not
saying you're you're getting angry or
anything like that but maybe maybe you
are it's
okay fear of judgment or reaction social
anxiety past experiences negative
experiences asking questions in group
mismatched expectation unmet needs
they're not met it can lead to
frustration or anger towards the group
leader lack of transparency so again I
am being very transparent with you as
part of that goes does that make
sense and so you know uh let's see
dominant participants a few dominate the
conversation lack of psychological
safety they don't feel secure or
respected I could I could do better at
this right here participants waste
responsibility on learning entirely on
the leader instead of it being a group
effort impostor syndrome perfectionism
emotional regulations strategies for
group leaders Foster a safe
environment uh actively work to create a
space by the way and this is how we're
going to end this watch this encourage
participation address questions
proactively provide feedback
channels What are some great ways that
leaders
can brainstorm some possibilities on
this as well as come up with additional
forms of
media music movies books Video Games
Etc that can actually
encourage these things put them below
again that's going to be
interesting creating a group environment
with psychological safety enables
members to feel secure and respected
demonstrate active listening by
summarizing what you said asking
follow-up
questions make an effort to engage
quieter group members by asking for
their input directly establish ground
rules share personal experiences
celebrate questions and curiosity this
instead of saying it's a silly
question offer Anonymous feedback
options facilitate group interaction
it's pretty good the culture code
secrets to highly successful groups
that's interesting dare to lead Freedom
Writers dead po Society yeah Lean on Me
life is strange that's video game an
undertale power of vulnerability by
Renee Brown building a psychologically
safe work place this is one I would be
interested to watching I can go find
this Ted Talk and watch
it and you can literally just then type
in a TED talk it's literally 11 minutes
long we can let's see if we can hack it
this
way take the
transcript we're going to say can you
brainstorm additional lessons
about fostering safety based on the
following and I'm literally going to
just take the comments
and copy those over as
well
encourage sharing experiences a failure
in learning to demonstrate vulnerability
train members to actively listen with
empathy that's good learn how to train
that better teach how to give and
receive feedback constructively create a
speakup culture facilitate inclusive
meetings dealing with disagreement
encourage cross functional collaboration
leadership for psychological safety
daring greatly yeah I love that book I
highly recommend yall read Darren
greatly The Fearless organization
interesting this might be a book that I
might pick
up inside out that's a really good one
that's all about like different parts
and things like that you will be found
dear I love that
song
Celeste interesting not heard of that
that
[Music]
video that's interesting that's a it's a
newer game huh highly ranked
too might check that one out all right
y'all there we go so that's going to
help you I think in just being a better
Coach getting yourself into the mindset
that you're looking for utilizing Ai and
media and entertainment to your
advantage to be able to tap you right
into the mindset the framework the brain
space that you're looking
for and you and you could literally do
the process that I just showed you in
this video for any Niche any topic and
start pulling in videos and transcripts
and even articles and stuff into this as
far as that goes and really start
to move into a whole new level of how
you do things my mom and I have done
this for years her and I both this
process in fact Danny Johnson is
actually one of the first people that I
know that she would do the same thing
thing uh Rick Peno is another another
one a lot of the best mentors that I
know actually do this process
subconsciously and they don't even know
they're doing
it and then I meet a lot of people
they're trying to succeed and they think
that what I just told you is like bad
and I'm
like it's actually lifechanging so all
right there we go